Guide to the Bernard Augustine De Voto Papers, 1918-1955 (inclusive), 1944-1951 (bulk) M0001
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Correspondence, 1918 - 1955; Series 1
  - Letters to BDV (incoming), Extensive cross-referencing for corporations, etc., Subseries 1.2
    - Heppler, J. (Box 13, Folder 255)
    - Herbert, P. - Hill, R. Jr. (Box 13, Folder 256)
    - History Book Club (R. Dovell), (2/46-1947) (Box 13, Folder 257)
    - History Book Club (R. Dovell), (3-4/47) (Box 13, Folder 258)
    - History Book Club (R. Dovell), (5-7/47) (Box 13, Folder 259)
    - History Book Club (R. Dovell), (8-3/47) (Box 13, Folder 260)
    - History Book Club (R. Dovell), (1948) (Box 13, Folder 261)
    - Hitch, M. - Hohoff, T. (Box 13, Folder 262)
    - Holbrook, S., (July 1943 - Feb. 1947) (Box 13, Folder 263)
    - Holbrook, S., (3/47-2/53) (Box 13, Folder 264)
    - Holden, J. - Homans, G. (Box 13, Folder 265)
    - Hoober, M. - Hough, G. (Box 13, Folder 266)
    - Houghton Mifflin, (1931-47) (Box 13, Folder 267)
    - Houghton Mifflin, (1948) (Box 13, Folder 268)
    - Houghton Mifflin, (1949) (Box 13, Folder 269)
    - Houghton Mifflin, (1950-55) (Box 13, Folder 270)
    - Howard, C. - Howard, J., (1946-47) (Box 13, Folder 271)
    - Howard, J., (1948-1951) (Box 13, Folder 272)
    - Howard, Josephine - Huntington, C. (Box 13, Folder 273)
    - Huntington, F. - Huntington Library (Hayden) (Box 13, Folder 274)
    - Hurlburt, B. (Box 13, Folder 275)
    - Hurley, L. - Hutchinson, R. (Box 13, Folder 276)
    - Hutchinson, W., (1946-54) (Box 14, Folder 277)
    - Hutchinson, W., (Jan. 1955) (Box 14, Folder 278)
    - Hutchinson, W., (8-3/55) (Box 14, Folder 279)
    - Huxley, A. - Hyperion Press (Crane) (Box 14, Folder 280)
    - Ickes, H. - Illinois State Hist. Society (Box 14, Folder 281)
    - Iowa State Univ. - Izaak Walton League of America (Box 14, Folder 282)
    - Jack, P. - Jastrow, J. (Box 14, Folder 283)
    - Jenkins, B. - Johnson, H. (Box 14, Folder 284)
    - Johnson, Joseph - Johnston, W. (Box 14, Folder 285)
    - Jones, C. - Jarvis, Mrs. W. (Box 14, Folder 286)
    - Kahler, H. - Kellock, K. (Box 14, Folder 287)
    - Kellogg, M. - Kilham, W. (Box 14, Folder 288)
    - King, G., (1916-19) (Box 14, Folder 289)
    - King, G., (1920 - May 1921) (Box 14, Folder 290)
    - King, G., (7/21 - 1925) (Box 14, Folder 291)
    - King, G., (1928) (Box 14, Folder 292)
    - King, G., (1929-30) (Box 14, Folder 293)
    - King, H. - Knight, J. (Box 14, Folder 294)
    - Knopf, (1927-46) (Box 14, Folder 295)
    - Knopf, (1947-48) (Box 14, Folder 296)
    - Knopf, (1949-55) (Box 14, Folder 297)
    - Knowles, B. - Kuberardt, P. (Box 14, Folder 298)
    - Kubie, L., (1941-42) (Box 14, Folder 299)
    - Kubie, L., (1945-47) (Box 15, Folder 300)
    - Kubie, L., (1948) (Box 15, Folder 301)
    - Kubie, L., (1949-55) (Box 15, Folder 302)
    - LaBonte, P. - Larch, F. (Box 15, Folder 303)
    - Lark, C. T. (Lit. exec. Twain estate), (1932-40) (Box 15, Folder 304)
    - Lark, C. T. (Lit. exec. Twain estate), (1932-40) (Box 15, Folder 305)
    - Lark, C. T. (Lit. exec. Twain estate), (1943) (Box 15, Folder 306)
    - Larkin, C. - Lehnhart, E. (Box 15, Folder 307)
    - Leigh, Inc., (1943-6/53) (Box 15, Folder 308)
    - Leigh, Inc., (8/53-7/54) (Box 15, Folder 309)
    - Leigh, Inc., (10/54-3/55) (Box 15, Folder 310)
    - Leigh, Inc., (Contracts & Itineraries) (Box 15, Folder 311)
    - Leisy, E. - Lewton, N. (Box 15, Folder 312)
    - Liddell, P. - Little, D. (Box 15, Folder 313)
    - Little Brown, (1926-40) (Box 15, Folder 314)
    - Little Brown, (1942-48) (Box 15, Folder 315)
    - Lively, M. - Lorimer, G. (Box 15, Folder 316)
    - Loring, P. - Lupper, F. (Box 15, Folder 317)
    - Luscomb, F. - Lyons, W. (Box 15, Folder 318)
    - McArdle, R. - McCullough, W. (Box 15, Folder 319)
    - McColloch, D. - McDowell, T. (Box 15, Folder 320)
    - McElwain, A. - McKeehan, J. (Box 16, Folder 321)
    - McKell, D. - McWilliams, C. (Box 16, Folder 322)
    - MacLeish, A. - Macy, G. (Box 16, Folder 323)
    - Macy, R. - Maloney, R. (Box 16, Folder 324)
    - Manfred, F. - March, F. (Box 16, Folder 325)
    - Marcus, S. - Matthiesson, F. O. (Box 16, Folder 326)
    - Mattingly, G., (1927-37) (Box 16, Folder 327)
    - Mattingly, G., (1938-42) (Box 16, Folder 328)
    - Mattingly, G., (1944-46) (Box 16, Folder 329)
    - Mattingly, G., (1947) (Box 16, Folder 330)
    - Mattingly, G., (1948-49) (Box 16, Folder 331)
    - Mattingly, G., (1950-51) (Box 16, Folder 332)
    - Mattingly, G., (1952-53) (Box 16, Folder 333)
    - Mattingly, G., (1954-55) (Box 16, Folder 334)
    - Mattuck, R. - Mellit, H. (Box 16, Folder 335)
    - Meine, F., (1929-39) (Box 16, Folder 336)
    - Meine, F., (1941-45) (Box 16, Folder 337)
    - Mencken, H., (1925-31) (Box 16, Folder 338)
      (see also: Am. Merc. Adv. Knopf)
    - Mencken, H., (1934-45) (Box 16, Folder 339)
    - Menefec, L. - Metcalf, E. (Box 16, Folder 340)
    - Metcalf, L. (Box 16, Folder 341)
    - Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer-Miller, George P. (Box 16, Folder 342)
    - Miller, George W. - Minton Balch (Box 16, Folder 343)
    - Mirrielees, E., (1933-34) (Box 16, Folder 344)
    - Mirrielees, E., (1935-44) (Box 16, Folder 345)
    - Mirrielees, E., (1946-49) (Box 17, Folder 346)
    - Mirrielees, E., (1950-55) (Box 17, Folder 347)
    - Mirrielees, L. - Mitchell, P. (Box 17, Folder 348)
    - Mock, H. - Moody, C. (Box 17, Folder 349)
    - Moody, P. - Mordell, A. (Box 17, Folder 350)
    - Morgan, D., (1941-44) (Box 17, Folder 351)
    - Morgan, D., (1945-54) (Box 17, Folder 352)
    - Morgan, H. - Morrison, J. (Box 17, Folder 353)
    - Morrison, T. (Bread Loaf), (see also: Harvard Phi Beta) (Box 17, Folder 354)
    - Morrow, D. - Moyer, D. (Box 17, Folder 355)
    - Mugridge, D. - Murdock, K. (Box 17, Folder 356)
    - Murdock, L. - Myers, I. (Box 17, Folder 357)
    - Nogel, C. - Natl. League of American Pen Women (Box 17, Folder 358)
    - Natl. Parks Assn. - Natl. Park Service, (1944-50) (Box 17, Folder 359)
    - Natl. Park Service, (1951-55) (Box 17, Folder 360)
    - Natl. War College - Neuberger, R. (Box 17, Folder 361)
    - [?] - Paramount (Box 17, Folder 362)
    - Pargellis, S. - Pearson, C. (Box 17, Folder 363)
    - Pearson, E. - Pendleton Chamber of Commerce (Box 17, Folder 364)
    - Penfold, J. - Perkin, R. (Box 17, Folder 365)
    - Perkins, A. - Peyton, R. (Box 18, Folder 366)
    - Pfost, G. - Port Angeles "Evening News" (Box 18, Folder 367)
    - Porter, Mr./Mrs. C., (1941-42) (Box 18, Folder 368)
      (see C. Curtis 12/6/44)
    - Porter, C., (1944-45) (Box 18, Folder 369)
    - Porter, C., (1947-55) (Box 18, Folder 370)
    - Porter, E. - Pratt, C. (Box 18, Folder 371)
    - Pratt, F. (Box 18, Folder 372)
    - Pratt, H. - Quintana, R. (Box 18, Folder 373)
    - R[?], Hank - Racca, V. (Box 18, Folder 374)
    - Raffelock, D. - Raywood, T. (Box 18, Folder 375)
    - Reader's Digest - Reid, G. (Box 18, Folder 376)
    - Reid, K. - Reporter (Horton) (Box 18, Folder 377)
    - Reves, E. (Box 18, Folder 378)
    - Rex, B. - Reynolds, R. (Box 18, Folder 379)
    - Rice, S. - Rivers of America, (see: Allen Harvey) (Box 18, Folder 380)
    - Roach, K. - Robertson, C. (Box 18, Folder 381)
    - Robeson Gallery - Roth, C. (Box 18, Folder 382)
    - Roth, R. (Box 18, Folder 383)
    - Rourke, C. (Box 18, Folder 384)
    - Roush, J. - Ryan, E. (Box 18, Folder 385)
    - St. Louis "Post-Dispatch" Sass, H. (Box 19, Folder 386)
    - Saturday Evening Post (Box 19, Folder 387)
    - Saturday Review of Literature (Box 19, Folder 388)
    - Sauers, C. - Sawyer, R. (Box 19, Folder 389)
    - Saxon, L. - Schleef, V. (Box 19, Folder 390)
    - Schlesinger, A. M. Jr. (Box 19, Folder 391)
    - Schlesinger, A. M. Sr. - Scott, S. (Box 19, Folder 392)
    - Scott, Walter D. - Scowcroft, R. (Box 19, Folder 393)
    - Searles, A. - Shively, G. (Box 19, Folder 394)
    - Shoben, E. - Sions, H. (Box 19, Folder 395)
    - Slade, F. - Sly, J. (Box 19, Folder 396)
    - Smart, C. - Smith, Marion (Box 19, Folder 397)
    - Smith, Melville - Snyder, R. (Box 19, Folder 398)
    - Soc. for the Prevention of Progress - Souvaine, M. (Box 19, Folder 399)
    - Sparks, E. - Sproule, R. (Box 19, Folder 400)
    - Stafford, M. - Stevens, G. (Box 19, Folder 401)
    - Stevenson, A. (Box 20, Folder 402)
    - Stewart, G. - Stout, G. (Box 20, Folder 403)
    - Stout, R. - Sturgis, S. (Box 20, Folder 404)
    - Sullivan, F. - Sykes, H. (Box 20, Folder 405)
    - Tafley, R. - Taylor, Frank (Box 20, Folder 406)
    - Taylor, George - Taylor, W. (Box 20, Folder 407)
    - Technocracy Inc. - Thwing, C. (Box 20, Folder 408)
    - Tolley, W. - Tyler, E. (Box 20, Folder 409)
    - Uhler, J. - Untermeyer, L. (Box 20, Folder 410)
    - Van de Mark, O. - Vars, E. (Box 20, Folder 411)
    - Velie, L. - Vitamin Quota (Box 20, Folder 412)
    - Vogt, W. - Voorhees, I. (Box 20, Folder 413)
    - W.L.S. - Waldron, W. (Box 20, Folder 414)
    - Waldrop, A. - Wagner, W. (Box 20, Folder 415)
    - War Dept. - Washburn, O. (Box 20, Folder 416)
    - Washington, Univ. of - Webster, S. (Box 20, Folder 417)
    - Wector, D., (1941-9/1946) (Box 20, Folder 418)
    - Wector, D., (10/46-1950) (Box 20, Folder 419)
    - Weed, E. - Westerling, F. (Box 20, Folder 420)
    - Western Humanities Review - Whistler, T. (Box 20, Folder 421)
    - White, C.C. - White, S. (Box 21, Folder 422)
    - Whiting, E. - Wildlife Mgmt. Inst. (Box 21, Folder 423)
    - Wilgus, W. - Williams, W. (Box 21, Folder 424)
    - Williamson, C. - Wilson, W. (Box 21, Folder 425)
    - Wilstach, J. - Withers, R. (Box 21, Folder 426)
    - Wolfe, F. - Woman's Day (Souvaine, Wheeler, McCaughey) (Box 21, Folder 427)
    - Wood, A. - Wood, T. (Box 21, Folder 428)
    - Woodbury, C. - Worthington, C. (Box 21, Folder 429)
    - Wray, J. - Writers' War Board (Box 21, Folder 430)
    - Wachinich, G. - Wyoming Wood Growers' Assn. (Box 21, Folder 431)
    - Yale Univ. Press - Zoss, B. (Box 21, Folder 432)
    - Miscellaneous., (1919-34) (Box 21, Folder 433)
      Names unknown.
    - Miscellaneous., (1935-49) (Box 21, Folder 434)
    - Miscellaneous., (1950-55) (Box 21, Folder 435)
    - Miscellaneous., (N.D.) (Box 21, Folder 436)
    - Letters about BDV (to B.S. Hurlburt) (Box 21, Folder 437)
    - Letters about BDV Army Enlistment, WW I. (Box 21, Folder 438)
    - Letters about BDV Harper's, 1-3/1955. (Box 21, Folder 439)
    - Letters about BDV Harper's, 4-6/1955. (Box 21, Folder 440)
    - Letters about BDV Harper's, 7-10/1955. (Box 21, Folder 441)
    - Letters about BDV Harper's, 11/55-3/56. (Box 21, Folder 442)
    - Letters about BDV Miscellaneous. (Box 21, Folder 443)
  - Other: Letters about Bernard De Voto's articles sent by Harper's to his widow, Subseries 1.3
    letters of condolence arranged alphabetically; letters of Mrs. DeVoto arranged chronologically.
    - A (Box 22, Folder 444)
    - B (Box 22, Folder 445)
    - C (Box 22, Folder 446)
    - D (Box 22, Folder 447)
    - E-F (Box 22, Folder 448)
    - G (Box 22, Folder 449)
    - H (Box 22, Folder 450)
    - J (Box 22, Folder 451)
    - K (Box 22, Folder 452)
    - L (Box 22, Folder 453)
    - Mc (Box 22, Folder 454)
    - M (Box 22, Folder 455)
    - N-O (Box 22, Folder 456)
    - P (Box 22, Folder 457)
    - R (Box 22, Folder 458)
    - Sa-Sl (Box 22, Folder 459)
    - Sm-Su (Box 22, Folder 460)
    - T-V (Box 22, Folder 461)
    - W-Z (Box 22, Folder 462)
    - Unidentified (Box 22, Folder 463)
    - Unidentified (Box 22, Folder 464)
    - Avis DeVoto Correspondence (Box 22, Folder 465)
- Biographical materials, Series 2
  - Genealogies - Family history, Do not photocopy This folder (Box 22, Folder 466)
  - Kent Potter Story (Box 22, Folder 467)
  - Kent Potter Story (Box 23, Folder 468)
  - Kent Hagler - Misc. (Box 23, Folder 469)
  - Kent Hagler Letters (Box 23, Folder 470)
  - Samuel Dye journal (Mormon grandfather) (Box 23, Folder 471)
  - Journals (Box 23, Folder 472)
  - Bucolics of Decadence (biography for Kate Sterne) (Box 24, Folder 473)
  - Contract re T.V. etc. between BDV, ADV and son (Box 24, Folder 474)
  - BDV bibliography (Box 24, Folder 475.1)
  - Holy Cross "Courier", May 1931 (Box 24, Folder 475.2)
    re Rose DeVoto Coffman
  - Bibliography by J. P. Barclay and E. H. Parnie (Box 24, Folder 475.3)
- Books, Series 3
  - Across the Wide Missouri, (Manuscript) (Box 25, Folder 475)
  - Across the Wide Missouri, (Typescript) (Box 25, Folder 475)
  - Across the Wide Missouri, (Typescript and Final) (Box 26, Folder 475)
  - Across the Wide Missouri, (Final Typescript) (Box 27, Folder 475)
  - Across the Wide Missouri, (Miller Notebook) (Box 27, Folder 47677)
  - Advance Agent, (Typescript I) (Box 28, Folder 477)
  - Advance Agent, (Typescript II) (Box 28, Folder 477)
  - Chariot of Fire (Burning Bush), (Ms.; Ts + carbon) (Box 29, Folder 477)
  - Cock Crow (unpubl.) ("The Winged Man" pp. 1-174) (Box 29, Folder 47880)
  - The Course of Empire, (Manuscript) (Box 30, Folder 480)
  - The Course of Empire, (Typescript 1-2) (Box 30, Folder 48182)
  - The Course of Empire, (Typescript 3-4) (Box 31, Folder 48399)
  - The Course of Empire, (Typescripts) (Box 32, Folder 50012)
  - The Course of Empire, (Typescripts) (Box 33, Folder 51335)
  - The Course of Empire, (Typescript; Galleys) (Box 34, Folder 53644)
  - The Course of Empire, (Galley -notes; unbound book; notes) (Box 35, Folder 54569)
  - The Hour, (Typescript) (Box 36, Folder 583)
  - The Easy Chair, (Typescript + carbon) (Box 36, Folder 57082)
  - The Third Generation, (TMs [UNK]) (Box 37, Folder 589)
  - The House of Sun-Goes-Down, (Partial Ms.) (Box 37, Folder 5834)
  - The Third Generation, (Ms. partial; 2 Tss.) (Box 37, Folder 58589)
  - The Journals of Lewis and Clark, (Ms.+Tss.) (Box 38, Folder 59097)
  - The Journals of Lewis and Clark, (Typescript) (Box 39, Folder 598615)
  - Mark Twain's America, (Galleys) (Box 40, Folder 61620)
  - The Journals of Lewis and Clark, (Typescript) (Box 40, Folder 61620)
  - Mark Twain's America, (Partial Ms.; Ts.) (Box 40, Folder 62126)
  - Mark Twain's America, (Warner Bros. scenario; Ts.) (Box 41, Folder 62729)
  - Mountain Time, (2 Typescripts) (Box 41, Folder 63035)
  - Mountain Time, (Prologue; Ms. 1+2) (Box 42, Folder 63645)
  - Mountain Time, (Pre-Collier's Ts; Collier's Ts.; Final Carbon) (Box 43, Folder 64659)
  - Mountain Time, (Typescript) (Box 44, Folder 66066)
  - We Accept With Pleasure, (Manuscript) (Box 44, Folder 66773)
  - The World of Fiction, (Typescripts 1+2) (Box 44, Folder 67480)
  - The World of Fiction, (Typescript 3) (Box 45, Folder 68184)
  - The Year of Decision: 1846, (Ms.; Ts. 1-6) (Box 45, Folder 68598)
  - The Year of Decision: 1846, (Typescript 7-17) (Box 46, Folder 699704)
  - The Year of Decision: 1846, (Typescript 7-17) (Box 46, Folder 699704)
  - The Year of Decision: 1846 (Atlantic Monthly) (Box 47, Folder 70521)
  - The works of Bernard De Voto: galleys (Box 82, Folder 182)
- Articles, Reviews, Speeches, Etc., Series 4
  - Articles (Conservation), Subseries 4.1
    Arranged alphabetically by titles, or suggested titles within an alphabetical subject arrangement. Speeches arranged chronologically. Lecture notes.
    - Speech on D'Ewart Bill -, 1953.; (1st p. missing) (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Speech - Denver Conservation Conference, 9/27/48. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - "Shall We Let Them Ruin Our National Parks?" Post, 7/22/50.; Untitled MS. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - "Firefighting by the Book" and "Jack of 465 Trades". Publ. unidentified - two titles of same article. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - "The Smoke Jumpers" Harper's, 11/51.; Untitled MS. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Speech - New Mexico, 1954. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Hail Columbia by G. Sundburg (review). NYHT, 6/27/54. (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - "Horse Opera in Modern Dress." Publ. unidentified. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - "Kiwanis Saves a Watershed". (DeVoto says he wrote this for Look, 1948.)Publ. unidentified. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - On National Parks. Fortune, 6/47. (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Proposals for articles on White Mtn. Natl. Forest N.H. and on two forest fires. (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Public Lands and Senate Bill 1149. (Box 47, Folder 12)
      (Probably a letter to a Congressman, 1953?).
    - "The Range War, 1951."; Publ. unidentified. (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - "Turning Back the Desert Threat."U. of Colorado Bulletin, 7/48. (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - "Uncle Sam's Campgrounds" Ford Times, 6/56. (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - "U.S. Forest Service" Holiday, 8/56. (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Easy Chair, Harper's, 1/48 (Box 47, Folder 17)
      on the Western Land Grab.
  - Articles (Historical), Subseries 4.2
    - The Age of Jackson by A.M. Schlesinger, Jr. (Review) "When Social History Becomes Literature." SRL, 9/16/45. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - The American People by Gorer (Review) "More Americans Than Not" NYHT Books, 3/28/48 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - The Mystery of "A Public Man" by Frank Maloy Anderson (Review) Publ. unidentified (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - The Diary of a Public Man by Bullard Harper's, Easy Chair, 5/45 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - "Geopolitics with Dew on It" Harper's, 3/44 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - "The Historian on Tour" W-Day, 6/47 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - History books of 1947 Untitled Publ. unidentified (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Indiana Home by Dr. Logan Esaroy (Review) American in Books, 6/47 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - "This Nettle, Danger" "We Grew Up with Danger" W-Day, 7/50 (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - The Parkman Reader, edited by Samuel E. Morison (Review)NEQ, 6/55 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Pursuit of the Horizon by Lord Haberly (Review) "Egnimatic Friend of the Indians", NYHT Books, 12/29/48 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - "The USA" International House Quarterly, 4/4/49 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - "Westward the Course of Empire" Publ. unidentified (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - "James P. Beckwitn" Hdwrth Publ. Unid., 1927; MS (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - "Disaster Long Ago" W-Day, 2/54 (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - "Far Western Trails" Purchased by The Lamp, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - "Frontier Family Medicine" Publ. unidentified (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - "The Indian All Around Us" Reader's Digest, 4/53 (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - "An Inference Regarding the Expedition of Lewis And Clarke" Proc. of the Am. Phil. Society, 8/30/55 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Lewis and Clark: Partners in Discovery by John Bakeless (Review) "Explorers Who Brought in the Northwest" NYHT Books, 12/21/47 (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - "The Louisiana Purchase" Colliers, March 21, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - A Mormon Frontier by N. Anderson (Review) Publication unidentified (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - "Oxtean West by Air" Also called "South Pass by Air" Harper's EC, July, 1950 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - "The Trail of Lewis and Clark" Publ. unidentified (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - "Canoes and Voyageurs" Entitled "The White Water Riverman" Holiday, October, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - "Bread Loaf, Vermont" Ford Times, May, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - "The Champlain Corridor" New title "Playtime Paradise" W-Day, Aug., 1953 (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - "Our Longest War" Ford Times, Feb., 1959 (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - "Hell's Half Acre, Mass" Harper's, Easy Chair, August, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - "Home Thoughts from Vermont" The Pan, March, 1939 (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - "New England" (Early title "Yankee Republic") Holiday, July, 1955 (Box 48, Folder 31)
    - "Plymouth Cemetery" New title "Coolidge's Grave in Plymouth Cemetery" New England Journeys #4, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - "Yankee Reserve" Harper's, Easy Chair, August, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - Civil War and Lincoln the President by J.G. Randall, Harper's, Easy Chair, February, 1946 and March, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 34)
    - Part II of Review of J.G. Randall, Lincoln the President, Easy Chair, March, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 35)
    - Grant and His Captains by C.E. Macartney (Report) Publication undetermined (Box 48, Folder 36)
    - Lee's Lieutenants by D.S. Freeman (Review) (Box 48, Folder 37)
      Vol.I -SRL -10/24/42 -- Vol.II -SRL -3/24/43
    - Lincoln Finds a General by K. Williams (Review) "Masterly Report on Civil War Generalship" NYHT Books, Nov., 2, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 38)
    - "Who Has Slighted the South?" New title "That Southern Inferiority Complex" Post, Nov. 16, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 39)
    - Essay Letter to A.M. Schlesinger on western books (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - The Centennial of [unknown] (Box 48, Folder 40)
    - "Dearborn" Ford Times, July, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 41)
    - "The Future of the West" Publication unidentified (Box 48, Folder 42)
    - "High Country" W-Day, May, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 43)
    - "Hurried Crossing" W-Day, May, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 44)
    - "The Intermountain West" Publication unidentified (Box 48, Folder 45)
    - "The Egypt of the West" Harper's, Easy Chair, June, 1943 (Box 48, Folder 46)
    - "Ogden" New title "A Good Place to Grow In" Lincoln-Mercury Times, March-April, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 47)
    - "Ore for the Rouge" Lincoln-Mercury Times, May-June, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 48)
    - Notes for unknown [unknown] (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - "Remember about the West" Publication unidentified (Box 48, Folder 49)
    - "Traveling the Louisiana Purchase" Titled "Louisiana Purchase" Collier's, March, 1953 (Box 48, Folder 50)
    - "Utah" American Mercury, March, 1926; (This is galley, not typescript) (Box 48, Folder 51)
    - "The Wasatch" New title "Let Me Tell You about the Wasatch" Lincoln-Mercury Times, July-August, 1956 (Box 48, Folder 52)
    - "The Wild West" Holiday, July, 1954 (Box 48, Folder 53)
  - Articles, Literary, Subseries 4.3
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare by Henry Miller (Review) NYT Books, Jan., 27, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Attitudes of contemporary writers, entitled "Time Without a Theme" SRL, August, 1949 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - "Birth of an Art" Harper's, Easy Chair, Dec. 1955 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - "The Constant Function" Harper's, Easy Chair, Oct. 1950 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - "A Demurrer" Middlebury College News letter, March 1938 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - "Emily Dickenson" Harper's, Easy Chair, June 1945 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - "The Fallacy of Excess Interpretation" (Box 49, Folder 7)
      Not this article but 4 pp notes about
    - Two drafts of an article on fiction unfinished, with note from ADV (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - On the Historical Novel, untitled, unidentified (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "Homicide in the Home," W-Day, July 1953 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Introduction toThe One-Eyed Poacher in the Maine Woods by Edmund Ware Smith, N.Y., 1955 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Untitled Easy Chair, Nov. 1955 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Mark Twain Books--3 reviews (Box 49, Folder 13)
      1. Mark Twain's Notebook by Albert Bigelow Paine -- Mark Twain: The Man and his Work by Edward Wagenknecht, New England Quarterly, June, 1936 -- 2. Mark Twain:Representation Selections / Ed. by Fred Pattes, New England Quarterly, Sept, 1935 -- 3. A Mark Twain Dictionary / Ed. by Caroline Thomas Harnsberger, Publication unidentified
    - Melville, untitled, Publication unidentified (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Mountain Time Radio [UNK] (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - A note on Hamlet written for This Week (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - The Naked and the Dead by Norman Mailer (Box 49, Folder 17)
      Pre-publication review
    - "The Novelist of the Cattle Kingdom," introduction to "The Hired Man on Horseback," by Gene Rhodes (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Notes on Ethan Frome, Edith Wharton. -- Publication unidentified (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - On a Note of Triumph / Norman Corwin, radio program -- Harper's, E.C., July, 1945 (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - The people, Yes / by Carl Sandburg, review. -- Publication unidentified (Box 49, Folder 21)
    - "Pocket Guide to Horse Opera,"W-Day, July, 1951 (Box 49, Folder 22)